JUSTIN BRENNER

12775 Russell Dr | Wayland, MI 49348 (269) 225-9596 | justin.brenner@forgetechnologysolutions.com

SUMMARY

Full-stack Developer & Data Engineer with 6+ years of experience designing/developing data architecture and web applications for enhanced operational output, I am a collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities dedicated to architecting a variety of solutions to increase organizational performance and automation.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Stryker Corporation

December 2021 to Present

Stryker Corporation | Kalamazoo, MI

Stryker is the world's leading manufacturer and marketer of major health care products. Its products include surgical hand pieces, hospital beds, medical implants, surgical robotics, and disposables.

Application Developer | Procurement COE

I am working with the procurement COE function to develop the architecture which will support the Procurement Analytics Center of Excellence (PACE) project. Within this project I am responsible for supporting data engineering relevant to the Data Vault 2.0 methodology with our IT partners and consultants: as well as developing all front-end and back-end applications/workloads for business processes. Each application will be developed in React.js utilizing an Azure back-end connecting to multiple REST API's and data factory pipeline outputs. This role requires continuity of communication with our internal customers as well as external consultants to ensure that all requirements are captured and implemented as required.

Some key skills used in this position:

- React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, Ruby on Rails
- Azure
- Machine learning using NVIDIA Clara, AWS ML Tools, Azure ML Tools
- Data engineering tools such as Python, R, Java and Scala
- Version control using Azure Agile DevOps processes

Staff Data Engineer | Data Architecture/Analytics February 2019 to December 2021

I was responsible for developing a global analytics strategy for the Global Quality and Operations side of the business utilizing Azure tools and services to create, deploy and manage our businesses data architecture and analytics. I have built several data storage systems with complex ETL designs in Azure and Alteryx to bring data to its final destination for reporting: utilizing Stryker's existing data sources such as our global eQMS/eCAPA management system (TrackWise) along with multiple ERP and financial systems including some external API sources from OpenFDA. Additionally, I have built several PowerApps and validated .NET and Vue.js web applications from an MVC design pattern hosted in Azure to enhance manufacturing and safety productivity based on user requirements; using SSO authentication, custom JavaScript classes/methods, and CSS to accommodate company brand.

Some key skills used in this position:

- Creating powerful business analytics through platforms such as MS Power BI, MS Power Apps and Tableau interfacing with ERP, SaaS CUBEs, SQL Servers, etc.
- Machine learning using NVIDIA Clara, AWS ML Tools, Azure ML Tools
- Vue.js, React.js, .NET, Ruby on Rails, Angular JS, Java
- GCP, Azure, AWS
- Version control using DevOps

Sr. Supplier Quality Engineer | Printed Circuit Boards, Software Bundles, and Plastic Injection Molding June 2016 to January 2019

I was responsible for managing over 400 components across 62 Suppliers providing PCBA, electrical assemblies and plastic injection molded components. I have driven corrective actions to defect concerns with Stryker's suppliers, addressing eCAPA related incidents (NCs / CAPAs) through the utilization of self-built analytical tools that interfaced with our suppliers to drive further process efficiency. I have been supporting supplier's process stability through creating and maintaining supplier's component / sub-assembly PPAP documentation, due to new product introductions, supplier-initiated requests, or process improvements which include process flow, control plans, PFMEAs and equipment / process capability.

Some key skills used in this position:

- Developed analytics reports using a combination of Power BI, React.js and Azure cloud
- Assisting R&D with new test method development and validation
- Utilizing statistical techniques to ensure Supplier process adequacy to maintain determined level of DPM
- Partnering with Operations in the investigation / correction of process failures
- Performing Process / Production Control Plan Audits
- Contributing in audits conducted through internal or external auditing bodies
- Communicating DFM guidelines and DFSS to R&D to ensure component manufacturability

Sr. Failure Analysis Engineer | Post-Commerce Complaints, Field Service Support, and New Product Development April 2015 to June 2016

I performed product / component complaint investigations to determine the root cause of electrical, software, and electro-mechanical failures in post-market products returned to Stryker. I acted as the technical liaison between sales reps and customers to provide support in the field, while ensuring that the appropriate corrective actions for out-of-box failures had been addressed internally at Stryker. I developed custom software analysis programs to root-cause devices and data compilation for trending purposes.

Some key skills used in this position:

- Developed web applications that interfaced with our hospitals to retrieve data from our System 7 batteries to provide our team with relevant failure related details upon return to the manufacturing facility.
- Analyzed ultrasonic aspiration system schematics and performing relevant tests to root-cause failures
- Conducted TM analysis / quantization of production chemicals and residues
- Utilized statistical techniques to influence pre-commerce product design verification tests
- Characterized components using: FTIR, TXRF, UV-Vis, SEM, TOC, Mass spectrometry, CMM

Forge Solutions LLC

June 2020 to Present

Forge Solutions | Paw Paw, MI

Full stack Development, Cloud Computing, Data Engineering, Application Services.

Owned more than 20 projects from initial research and conceptual design through testing and implementation phases.

Project mentions

Dimse:

DIMSE is a Full stack SaaS Web Portal for radiology practices; DIMSE is an instant medical imaging solution for radiology practices, research, imaging centers and hospitals. Utilizing AWS, GCP & Azure as a C-STORE to the cloud, Zero install OHIF Viewers and operational dashboards to maximize efficiency. Powered by professionally implemented services, state of the art GPUs and open technologies with global reach.

Surplus List:

Surplus List is a Full stack SaaS real-estate platform used for Skip Tracing properties and persons to locate Surplus Funds associated with Tax, Mortgage, and foreclosure overages. The platform uses AWS to handle all application management services and data architecture; users send requests containing query parameters and an authentication token to an API gateway that utilizes a static IP address to run the requests with the API provider and much more.

Perrigo Company plc

Sep 2012 to June 2013

Perrigo Company | Allegan, MI

A leading global healthcare company, delivers value to its customers and consumers by providing Quality Affordable Healthcare Products.

Associate QC Chemist | Formulations (Solid Oral Dosage Formulations)

I evaluated compendial monograph and test method proposals, supporting compliance for product affected by raw pharmaceutical materials and finished OTC products. I provided support to develop complex analytical techniques such as chromatography (HPLC, UPLC, GC), spectroscopy (AA, UV, FTIR), and other test methods. I applied methods of chemical analysis to ensure product quality, ensuring molecular elements of the drugs / raw materials structure are easy to determine for toxicological and pharmacological purposes.

Brenner Oil Corporation

June 2011 to June 2014

Brenner Oil Corporation | Holland, MI

Brenner Oil sets the pace for West Michigan's oil delivery industry as one of the Top 20.

Quality Assurance Project Engineer | Internal Oil Reprocessing and Logistics

I developed quality control and periodic maintenance standards, for equipment, tools and processes in the discipline areas of pressure equipment, certified service equipment, and electrical wiring. I led SAP ERP implementation to manage high-volume operations that integrated supply chain logistics with warehouse and distribution processes to optimize inventory traceability, cross-docking and distribution operations in real time. Monitored distribution operations using SAP Analytics Cloud to make better decisions backed by data.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Libraries (Vue.JS, React.js, Next.js)
- Frameworks (MUI, Grommet, Redux, ASP.NET, Ruby on Rails, Angular JS, Java)
- Azure Services (Data Lake, Data factory (ADF), Azure App Service, Azure API Management, Azure Databricks,
 Azure SQL database, Azure SQL Datawarehouse
- External API integration into applications
- MS PowerApps, Flow (Power Automate)
- MS Office applications (Access, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Word)
- ERP System management (AS400, Oracle, SAP)
- Business analytics platforms (Power BI, SAP Analytics, Tableau, Qlik, Oracle)
- Data management (SQL, Azure, AWS, GCP, RScript (statistics), Attivio)
- Root cause analysis tools (Fishbone, 5-why, human error, Shanin quality principles, Red-X, 8D)
- Technical design, Data verification & validation test methods

EDUCATION

Calvin College | Grand Rapids, MI 2.8 GPA

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS (Amazon Web Services)

- <u>Certified Developer</u>
- Certified Solutions Architect
- Certified Machine Learning Specialty
- Certified DevOps Engineer